Talk about close!
Glad I dug that.
At this very moment,
I'm working my way through another world alone!
Loner With the Worst Skills
Let's take things back to the day I got transported.
I was spending lunch reading like always.
All alone, as you can see.
As anyone can see.
Yup. I lived a loner life in the real world, too.
Quit rubbing it in! You're not wrong, but still!
So why was I alone? That's easy.
Because I wanted nothing to do with my classmates.
They'd get in the way of my books.
If I had to divide up the class, it'd be...
...the delinquents.
The valley gal sort.
The jocks.
The nerds.
The class reps.
Then there's just... the rest.
And me, not part of any group.
That's when it happened.
Holy crap!
Wha-?!
What is that?!
A magic circle?! Just like the one
in the light novel I was reading?!
I got excited for a quick second,
before realizing an isekai would be a pain in the ass.
I'll stick to the sort in my books.
Dunno who's doing this, but no thanks!
It was like my body had a mind of its own,
trying desperately to leave the classroom.
And it REALLY tried.
Yeah, I figured. That's how these things go.
No way!
My body's disappearing!
No freakin' way!
Whadda we do?
What's goin' on?!
Gimme a freaking break!
Are we...?
Only one way out!
My last hope was up into the ceiling.
Phew, doubt it'll reach me up here...
Noooo!
Ugh, I'm in for it now.
The ol' nothing-but-white room.
So uhh, why is no one else here?
Isn't there usually some fatso king or a beautiful princess
no geek would ever meet in real life?
Hmm? That old guy's all alone like me.
The old dude was in a panic.
Why are you here?!
Everyone's gone!
Turns out he's some god in this place.
Hurry and get ready!
Apparently, the rest of the class
was out in the new world already.
I was the only one left.
Guess even the omniscient
overlooked my little escape route!
He urged me to hurry.
It's first-come first-served!
And so I had to set my isekai stats and such.
Got to set your stats!
WEAPON ARTS
IAIDO SWORDSMANSHIP
DUAL BLADES
GREATSWORDS
SHIELDS
COMET STRIKE
DAGGERS
Normally, each person gets 50 points to use
on skills and magic and such.
WEAPON ARTS
IAIDO SWORDSMANSHIP
DUAL BLADES
GREATSWORDS
SHIELDS
COMET STRIKE
DAGGERS
But this was the old man's first time
roping in 43 people at once.
SHIELD APTITUDE
COMBAT APTITUDE
BOW APTITUDE
MAGIC APTITUDE
DUMMY
COMPANY COMMUNICATOR
MASTER OF NONE
Apparently, the OP skills were first-come first-served,
and the rest were all crap.
Still, I figured I'd better take a good look.
POINT
ALLOCATION
FOR STATS
YOU MAY ALLOCATE 1 POINT TO EACH STAT
OR ROLL DICE (10P FOR 2 DICE)
Definitely not going for dice.
Even if I got two sixes, that'd only put me at 12.
What kind of moron would go for that?
EQUIPMENT
ITEMS
PALADIN SET                                     GREAT SAGE SET
VILLAGER A SET
ALCHEMIST SET
CONTACT LENSES
BLACK KNIGHT SET
RING                                   BERSERKER SET
ANTIDOTE
All that's left is a "Villager A Set" and "Contact Lenses"?!
Who the heck is Villager A? Talk about lame!
I wanted to be a Paladin or a Great Sage or something!
MARTIAL ARTS
DAGGERS
COMET STRIKE
SHIELDS
DEADLY BLOWS
SPEARS
STAVES
TWO-HANDED SWORDS
ONE-HANDED SWORDS
ARCHERY
"Staves"? A staff is basically just a stick!
Do you just hit things with sticks?
How do you survive an isekai like that?
Gimme a sword or a spear or something!
SKILL
EXP BOOST
PILLAGE
HEIGHTENED INTUITION          SWORDSMANSHIP
CLAIRVOYANCE
WELL-BEING                        WALKING
CALISTHENICS             SENSITIVITY
SORCERY
How are "Well-being" and "Walking" even skills?
Is there nothing else?!
I wanted something OP like Pillaging or Clairvoyance!
MAGIC
GRAND MAGIC                    FLAME         LIGHTNING            FIRE
HEALING
ELEMENTAL ASSIGNMENT
ELEMENTAL BOOST                    DEATH                       CHARM
TEMPERATURE             PACKING
WEIGHT                      MOVEMENT
DARK
Of course the go-to Grand Magic is gone.
No idea what the stuff left even does.
How can there even be crap magic?
SPECIAL
SHIELD APTITUDE
COMBAT APTITUDE
MAGIC APTITUDE
BOW APTITUDE
COMPANY COMMUNICATOR
MASTER OF NONE
DUMMY
What does "Company Communicator" even do?!
Am I supposed to be an office worker, here?
And how can "Dummy" be anything but bad?
TITLE
SAINT                                       FIEND SLAYER
NEET
SHUT-IN
ILLUSIONIST                         TACTICIAN                               GUARDIAN
Now shut-ins and NEETs?
How are slackers gonna take down monsters?
HEALTH
WALKING
CALISTHENICS
SENSITIVITY
Wait. That's it?
There's crap, and then there's this.
WHAT'S THE DEAL, OLD MAN?!
Skills like these won't even get me through the first town!
You gotta have better skills to choose from!
Can you not even estimate
how many people you're summoning?
And you call yourself a god?
Are you outta your mind? Seriously, are you?!
By then, the old man was sick of my complaints.
"Fine, take all the skills left! Now begone!" he said.
TEMPERATURE   PACKING
WEIGHT   MOVEMENT
COMPANY COMMUNICATOR
DUMMY
WELL-BEING   WALKING
CALISTHENICS SENSITIVITY
So I wound up with all the leftover crap,
and was basically guaranteed nightmare mode.
He seriously teleported me...
How am I supposed to handle an isekai outta nowhere?
I wasn't ready for this...
Then again, I guess no one ever is.
Huh?
I guess this must be...
...the Villager A Set.
Wait, can this thing hold infinite items?
Contacts                                                  Cloak                                          Leather Boots
Wooden Stick
Ring of the Dead Soul
Jewel of Knowledge
Villager A's Diary
Still looks like a bunch of leftover crap, but...
Not half bad!
So! Now that I look good, how are my stats?
Lemme just open "Check Stats," and...
Please roll the dice
What? Why dice?
YOU MAY ALLOCATE 1 POINT TO EACH STAT
OR ROLL DICE (10P FOR 2 DICE)
That old fart really stuck me with EVERYTHING!
Was he cleaning out stock or something?
What the heck?! What does "M" mean?
Please tell me it's not M for minus!
Or maybe M for masochism?
Certainly not that
Nice retort!
Which stat do you wish to allocate to?
Uhh...
Doesn't look like I'm gonna pull through
with any other strengths, so...
Put it on Luck.
Points allocated.
Which stat do you wish
to allocate to next?
Forget worrying about balance! Time to go all in!
Points allocated to Luck.
Now calculating stats
SPECIES:
HUMAN
MARTIAL ARTS:    CANE TECHNIQUE
MAGIC:          TEMPERATURE         MOVE                 WEIGHT           PACKING
SKILLS:              HEALTH           SENSITIVITY       CALISTHENICS     WALKING
My Luck skill is off the charts. So M stood for Max?!
RACE
HUMAN
The rest is still all crap.
MARTIAL ARTS:     CANE TECHNIQUE
MAGIC:        TEMPERATURE      MOVE              WEIGHT           PACKING
SKILLS:        HEALTH             SENSITIVITY        CALISTHENICS      WALKING
TITLE:                 SHUT-IN                       NEET                 LONER
COMPANY COMMUNICATOR   MASTER OF NONE        DUMMY
EQUIPMENT: CLOTH BAG
Wait, there are two extra.
Subjugate                                                                 Loner
SUBJUGATE OTHERS TO FOLLOW YOUR COMMAND                                                            MUST SURVIVE ALONE.
CANNOT FORM PARTY.
Additional Ability
IF YOU WANT
TO MAKE FRIENDS
Is that because I got pulled in alone?
Apparently, when you're a loner
you can use the subjugate skill.
Stuck alone in another world, huh?
There go my chances of an isekai harem.
Why's no one else around, though?
Everyone shoulda been sucked in here with me.
Ah, who cares? Can't form a party anyway!
Only thing I gotta worry about now
is setting up somewhere safe.
Then I just need to find some food.
Time to make myself a home!
Hard to see anything stuck in these woods, though.
If a monster rolled up on me now, I'd be done for.
Dunno if my well-honed fake sleeping ability
would do me any good.
Oh, yeah! I still haven't tried those contacts.
Whoa!
Nuts
These don't just let me see things!
Phsyical Strength Mushroom
Nuts
Medicinal Herbs
Potenshroom
They let me see EVERYTHING!
Antidote
Potion
Clear as day!
How do these even work?
These contacts give me the Appraisal skill?
This brings a lot into focus!
CONTACTS
APPRAISAL: ABILITY TO JUDGE ALL VISIBLE THINGS
Potenshroom
Edible. Boosts potential capacities.
My Appraisal skill opened up a whole new world.
Potenshroom
And made things more fun!
Whoa!
Bird
Nuts
Medicinal Herb
Potenshroom
Bird
Antidote Herb
Medicinal Herb
Bird
Nuts
Potenshroom
Medicinal Herb
Wow, look at these!
Potenshroom
EDIBLE.     BOOSTS POTENTIAL CAPACITIES.
Edible mushrooms!
My bag could hold everything I found,
and I had potions packed in already.
I really should apologize
for talking down the Villager A Set.
I feel like I can find anything out here...
Hmm?
Delish!
Huh?
A cave?
Anyone home?
Sorry for intruding if this is your home, monsters.
Really hope it's not, though!
Nice and spacious.
Magic Tent
CAN BE DEPLOYED OR PACKED UP USING MAGIC.
REMAINS ROOM TEMPERATURE.
WARDS OFF BUGS AND MONSTERS
Magic Lantern
CAN BE LIT, SET TO FLASH,
OR EXTINGUISHED USING MAGIC.
WARDS OFF BUGS AND MONSTERS.
Got a tent and a lamp in my bag, already.
Already feelin' like settling in.
Gathered up some wood and leaves.
Now to just use my Temperature magic and...
That should keep the beasts away.
This leftover magic isn't so bad!
Lemme just check my stats before I pass out.
MAGIC
Temperature   Movement   Weight
Packing        Fire Magic
Nice, my Temperature skill leveled up
and I got "Fire Magic".
MAGIC
Temperature   Movement   Weight
Packing        Fire Magic
SKILLS
Well-Being      Sensitivity       Calisthenics
Walking           Subjugation         Appraisal
Clairvoyance    Perception    Enemy Detection
Got Clairvoyance, Perception,
and "Enemy Detection", too.
I did make sure there were no baddies around...
But what if they show up...?
All I can do is hit them with a stick...
And just like that I finished my first day
as a loner in another world.
DAY 2
Whew, made it through the night no problem.
My items got a bonus monster repellent effect.
All thanks to that "Shut-in" title I got.
Nice going, shut-ins!
SHUT-IN:
SHUT SELF IN
PROTECTS LIVING SPACE.
My stomach's not fairing so well, though.
Time to light a fire with my new magic.
And mix the mushrooms I gathered
with the cured meat in my bag.
Add a little flavor, aaand...
Breakfast is served!
Delish! Gotta hand it to myself!
Didn't expect to have a pan and a knife.
The Villager A Set is doing wonders.
Did this A guy really live in a village, though?
He's more like some wilderness survivor.
Forget that, though.
Gotta figure out where I go from here.
That cave should work as a home for now.
Next up is finding food and working on security.
Stamina Caps
Medicinal Herb
The real problem will be monsters...
PERCEPTION
The time's come, huh?
Not one, but two goblins.
GOBLIN B
GOBLIN A
They should be pushover mobs,
but those are some high stats!
Can I win this?
I mean, out here I'm gonna have to fight eventually.
This could be my chance.
Not so sure about this stick, though...
Maybe I can try using "Packing"
to pack it full of magical energy.
PACKING
To pack various things with magic.
It can have a wide range of effects.
Sweet. Worked better than I thought.
Forget OP skills, I can make myself OP!
Right, one more to go.
It's attacks are simple.
Easy enough to read!
I survived my first battle.
It wasn't perfect, but I did good.
Passed with flying colors.
Took more mental damage than physical out there...
Club
A CLUB MADE OUT OF WOOD
I brought back one of the goblin clubs.
That it? This thing's short, heavy, and useless.
My stick's good enough for now.
All right, let's see, then...
RACE
HUMAN
Nice! I leveled up!
Whoa! And my stats basically doubled!
My Staves skill went up!
Just from smashing things with my stick?
MARTIAL ARTS:   STAVES              EVASION        ENEMY DETECTION     MAGIC WRAP
MAGIC:     TEMPERATURE      MOVEMENT         WEIGHT         PACKING       FIRE MAGIC
SKILLS:           WELL-BEING    SENSITIVITY     CALISTHENICS    WALKING      SUBJUGATE
TITLE:                 SHUT-IN                     NEET                   LONER
COMPANY COMMUNICATOR    MASTER OF NONE     DUMMY
WOODEN STICK  PLAIN CLOTHES   LEATHER GLOVES   LEATHER BOOTS   CAPE
Huh? My Sensitivity skill, too?
Don't even need to get captured by goblins
and tormented like some poor lady knight?
MARTIAL ARTS:   STAVES              EVASION        ENEMY DETECTION     MAGIC WRAP
MAGIC:        TEMPERATURE        MOVEMENT         WEIGHT               PACKING           FIRE MAGIC
SKILLS:              WELL-BEING       SENSITIVITY        CALISTHENICS    WALKING         SUBJUGATE
TITLE:                    SHUT-IN                        NEET                     LONER
COMPANY COMMUNICATOR    MASTER OF NONE     DUMMY
WOODEN STICK  PLAIN CLOTHES   LEATHER GLOVES   LEATHER BOOTS   CAPE
Got something called "Magic Wrap," too?
Maybe from packing magic into my stick?
Leveled up Calisthenics, too!
Must be cause I always do my morning stretches!
Err, as of today, at least...
DAY 3
I am so done with mushrooms...
I could really go for some meat, but...
I bet the Class Rep wouldn't approve.
SAY NO
TO INDULGENCE!
'Kay! First things first, I gotta toughen myself up.
My new Magic Wrap ability
MAGIC WRAP LV 1:
can boost my physical abilities plus my physical and
magic defense, putting most other skill sets to shame!
Magic Wrap
Corner
The isekai housewives would line up
for a bargain like this!
Wait, my Appraisal skill leveled up, too...
LEATHER GLOVES ?
CAPE ?
WOODEN STICK ?
So what's with all these question marks?
Seems worse to me.
Whatever. Forget about it!
Let's go out and have some fun! Yessiree!
Time to practice magic now, one-two-three!
All right! Nature's bounty is mine!
Ugh! No more mushrooms!
Where does all the meat grow, huh? Where?!
Wait, forget the mushrooms, it's magic time!
What am I even doing?
Magic Wrap.
Feels like that worked.
Light as a feather!
So fast it's like warping!
Whoa! And my attacks are faster than ever!
Now for some tougher goblins!
GOBLIN C
GOBLIN D
Piece of cake!
So long as there's only two, they don't stand a chance!
I'm already doing way better than yesterday!
Bet I could even handle three!
Maybe I'll let them off this time.
Gotta head home and practice my magic.
Fight
Items
Magic
Run
Haruka
Goblin A
Goblin B
From there on it was goblin hunting by day,
and magic research by night.
Or maybe more like DIY time? Just lots of trial and error.
Until day five.
When I beat a goblin in one hit!
Decorated my base a bit, too.
Feels like I've got the hang of this isekai thing.
Now to just keep it up.
YES! Meat at last!
Get back here!
A little meaty-treat, at last!
Gotcha!
PERCEPTION
That was no goblin...
Are those...?
Ugh...
Of course it has to be the class delinquents...
I don't want anything to do with them.
Wait.
There might be someone over there.
Clairvoyance!
Next it's the gal gang? You gotta be kidding!
And over there are the jocks?
Definitely don't wanna bump into them!
Even the nerds? I mean,
we used to talk sometimes, but...
no thanks!
The class rep...
This world is a vicious place.
I know it's better to have companions.
I've known the class rep
since our first day at elementary school, too.
Maybe I could just...
But, no...
All this freedom and isolation.
No one to tell me what to do!
Nothing can beat a life like this!
That's it! Of course it is!
I...
I am...
...gonna master this world alone!